<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chapter 2 on Precalculus 1 - Functions</title>
    <link>https://duragauge.github.io/chapter-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chapter 2 on Precalculus 1 - Functions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://duragauge.github.io/chapter-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2.1 Power Functions</title>
      <link>https://duragauge.github.io/chapter-2/2.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://duragauge.github.io/chapter-2/2.1/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Daian Gan from PexelsIntroduction Part of the enjoyment of art comes from its patterns of sound and color and motion.
Patterns are also an essential part of mathematics. The British mathematician G. H. Hardy once said that &amp;quot;A mathematician, like a painter or a poet, is a maker of patterns. If his patterns are more permanent than theirs, it is because they are made with ideas&amp;quot;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2.2 Applications of Power Functions</title>
      <link>https://duragauge.github.io/chapter-2/2.2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://duragauge.github.io/chapter-2/2.2/</guid>
      <description>Apollo 15Introduction In 1687 Isaac Newton published Principia, one of the most important books in the history of science.  A rare first edition copy of Principia sold at auction for $3.7 million in 2016. In Principia Newton formulated his three laws of motion, expanded Kepler&#39;s work on planetary orbits, laid the foundations for classical mechanics and, for the first time ever, gave a mathematical description of gravity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2.3 Equations Involving Power Functions</title>
      <link>https://duragauge.github.io/chapter-2/2.3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://duragauge.github.io/chapter-2/2.3/</guid>
      <description>Photo from the US Air Force on FlickrIntroduction Do skydivers fall at a constant speed or do they go faster and faster the longer they fall? Is there anything they can do to control their speed or is it completely out of their hands?
After we spend a moment outlining the basic solving process for power functions, we will return to these questions.
Techniques for Solving Power Equations Since most equations involving power functions will be of the form $y = k x^{p}$, the steps for solving all of them are essentially the same.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
