<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chapter 6 on Precalculus 1 - Functions</title>
    <link>https://duragauge.github.io/chapter-6/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chapter 6 on Precalculus 1 - Functions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://duragauge.github.io/chapter-6/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>6.1 Concepts of Modeling</title>
      <link>https://duragauge.github.io/chapter-6/6.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://duragauge.github.io/chapter-6/6.1/</guid>
      <description>Tornado photo by Nikolas Noonan on UnsplashIntroduction Every spring, hundreds of people come to the Great Plains region of the United States in an attempt to get as close as possible to one of nature&#39;s most violent events: a tornado. While some go to &amp;quot;Tornado Alley&amp;quot; just for the thrill, most professional storm chasers have a different goal. What they want is data: scientific measurements that can only be found inside real tornadoes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6.2 Algebraic Methods for Modeling</title>
      <link>https://duragauge.github.io/chapter-6/6.2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://duragauge.github.io/chapter-6/6.2/</guid>
      <description>Image by Design n Print from PixabayIntroduction Many people are concerned about the amount of mercury they ingest by eating certain species of large fish like shark, swordfish, and tuna. Mercury levels in large fish can be over a million times higher than that found in the surrounding waters, posing a possible health risk.
An accurate mathematical model could help people understand those concerns and make informed decisions. Fortunately, the elimination of substances like mercury from the body are known to have biological half-lives, and we know that half-lives can be modeled with exponential functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6.3 Using Technology to Model Data</title>
      <link>https://duragauge.github.io/chapter-6/6.3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://duragauge.github.io/chapter-6/6.3/</guid>
      <description>Photo Steppinstars from Pixabay Introduction Throughout the vast grasslands of Nevada live herds of wild horses known as &amp;quot;mustangs&amp;quot;. The Bureau of Land Management (BLM) has been diligently monitoring the number of mustangs and the land&#39;s capacity to support them since 1971.
A function model of that data could be used to predict the future size of the mustang herds, helping the BLM plan actions to help the herds thrive.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
