<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chapter 5 on Precalculus 1 - Functions</title>
    <link>https://duragauge.github.io/chapter-5/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chapter 5 on Precalculus 1 - Functions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://duragauge.github.io/chapter-5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>5.1 Graphs of Polynomials</title>
      <link>https://duragauge.github.io/chapter-5/5.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://duragauge.github.io/chapter-5/5.1/</guid>
      <description>Statue of Al-Khwārizmī in his birth town Khiva, Uzbekistan. Photo by Yunuskhuja Tuygunkhujaev on WikipediaIntroduction Polynomials have intrigued mathematicians for centuries. Ancient Egyptian, Babylonian, and Greek mathematicians all studied simple polynomials.
The Chinese are known to have worked with cubics in the early 7th century, at the same time mathematicians in India were busy creating the quadratic formula.
Two centuries later the Persian mathematician al-Khwārizmī introduced the world to “al-jabr”, or “algebra”, as a process for solving polynomial equations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5.2 Zeros &amp; Polynomial Equations</title>
      <link>https://duragauge.github.io/chapter-5/5.2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://duragauge.github.io/chapter-5/5.2/</guid>
      <description>Drawing by Bauce and RougetIntroduction As the smoke cleared on the morning of May 30, 1832, young Évariste Galois lay mortally wounded on the ground, having been shot in the stomach. Though only 20 years old, Galois had earned a reputation not only as a brilliant mathematician, but also as a reckless political activist who had threatened the life of the French king and been arrested for carrying loaded weapons during a protest in Paris.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5.3 Applications of Polynomials</title>
      <link>https://duragauge.github.io/chapter-5/5.3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://duragauge.github.io/chapter-5/5.3/</guid>
      <description>Photo by granadandyou from Pixabay Introduction Located in the foothills of the Sierra Nevada mountains in the Andalusia region of Spain, the Alhambra palace is a world heritage site from the 13th century. Among it&#39;s most photographed features today are the water fountains in the Generalife gardens.
The water that flows out of these fountains follows a curved path through the air. But it&#39;s not just any random curve, it is a parabola!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5.4 Rational Functions</title>
      <link>https://duragauge.github.io/chapter-5/5.4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://duragauge.github.io/chapter-5/5.4/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Erik Mclean on UnsplashIntroduction Some observable characteristics, such as eye and hair color, are controlled by genes that pass from parent to child. It&#39;s not unusual for a trait to skip generations and appear to pop up out of nowhere. For instance, two people who don&#39;t have red hair can have redheaded children, or someone might have blue eyes even if both parents have brown eyes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
